Josephine Butler 134
People's Archive, MLK Library
Josephine Butler Papers
1965-2006
People's Archive, MLK Library
Butler, Josephine
134
20 Linear feet
Josephine Butler co-founded the D.C. Statehood Movement with Julius Hobson. She was a staunch proponent of city parks and recreation places for families, children and communities throughout the city. Butler's work led to the desegregation of city schools, establishment of safe spaces for children, and the development health care reform. The Josephine Butler Papers document Butler's career as a community activist and contain subject files on organizations she was involved with and causes she fought for.
Biographical / Historical
Josephine Butler was born in Brandywine, Maryland, and lived her life in the greater Washington, D.C. area. Butler's grandparents were enslaved and she grew up with parents who were sharecroppers, so she strived to make the world a better place to live for hardworking people and children. Butler was an amazing community activist, organizer and political heavy-weight. She was involved in almost every critical political movement that occurred in the greater Washington, D.C. area. Because Black women were relegated to more menial jobs during the segregation and Jim Crow era, there were multitudes of black female laundresses. In order to support the development of rights and respect for black women in the domestic field, Butler founded the first union that supported Black female laundry workers in the city. She co-founded the D.C. Statehood Movement with Julius Hobson. She was a staunch proponent of city parks and recreation places for families, children and communities throughout the city. Butler's work led to the desegregation of city schools, establishment of safe spaces for children, and the development health care reform. Butler founded the D.C. Chapter of the Paul Robeson Friendship Association and the Friends of Meridian Hill Association. Butler was very close to Hobson as well as Hilda Mason.
Scope and Contents
The Josephine Butler Papers document Butler's career as a community activist and contain subject files on organizations she was involved with and causes she fought for. Most prominently featured are files on the DC Statehood party and movement. Also included are files on the Friendship Society, the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, and the US-Grenada Friendship Society.
Women; African Americans; Black persons; Community activists
- Series 1
  - Newspapers 1 of 2, 1978-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers 2 of 2, 1974-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mary McLeod Articles and Documents, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Programs and Pamphlets, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Soviet Uzbekistan, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Applications and Health Info, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Women's Activism Documents and Ads, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cards/Invitations/Post Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Superior Court Order, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Position Papers, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Healthcare Invoices and Claims Forms, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Campaign Planning - Position Descriptions and Press Release, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Josephine Butler Campaign Advertisements, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Paul Robeson Articles (1 of 3), 1976-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Paul Robeson Articles (2 of 3), 1976-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Paul Robeson Articles (3 of 3), 1976-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Union Articles and Related Papers, 1979-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Paul Robeson Newspaper Articles, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Civil Rights Articles, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Statehood and Salutation and Articles, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hansib Community Awards, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Alternative Housing D.C., undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - New World Review, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The People's Windward Island Shipwrights, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Invitation List, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Israeli Palestinian Articles and Articles on Ethiopia 1 (1 of 2), 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Israeli Palestinian Articles and Articles on Ethiopia 1 (2 of 2), 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Palestine Aid Society Papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Freedomways, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ADC Reports, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - World Peace Council - Session of the Presidential Committee Meeting, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee Member Letter, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Legal Aid Pamphlet, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - ADC National Convention Invitation, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Lawrence Guyot ANC Ibol Flyer, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Free West Indian - The National Newspaper of Free Grenada, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - PHRC Meeting Sign in Sheet, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Survival Fest 84, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - One Year Later: The Prisoners at Ansar, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - The Link: The Sorrow of Lebanon Journal, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Sabra Shatilia Commemoration Committee Publication, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Middle East Peace Action Coalition Minutes, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Freedom for Ziad Stickers, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Memorandum on Human Rights Conditions, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - ADC Action Alerts and Reports, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Taking Root Bearing Fruit, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Articles and Journals about Grenada, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Joint Committee for Women's Rights - Article on Maternity Leave Struggle in Jamaica, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Josephine Butler Story Article, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The People's Windward Island Shipwrights Charts, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Address Stickers and Lists, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - US Grenada Friendship Society Bulletins - New Releases and Bylaws, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Articles on the Caribbean, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Studies on Puerto Rico and History, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Prime Minister Maurice Bishop New Year Message, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Festival of the Revolution Address List, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - State Department Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - List of Interventions in the Caribbean - 1900-1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Grenada Discussion Poster, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Articles, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Carribean Conference of Chruches Points and Initiative, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - First International Conference in Solidarity, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Resolution on Grenada, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Solidarity Sign in Sheet, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - US Grenada Friendship Society Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - US Grenada Friendship Society Meeting Minutes and Cash Reports, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Grenada Friendship Society Petition, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - New World Review Newsletter, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - National Conference on Women, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Fidel Castro Main Report, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Tony Lee's Lecture about Visiting the Soviet Union, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Friendship News Newsletters, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - City of Magnificent Intentions, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Constitution of the State of Columbia, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Congress Roster, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Congratulations Card, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Breira- A Project of Concern in Diaspora-Israel Relations Peace Now, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Longest Walk, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Exclusive: Angela Answers 13 Questions, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - People to People: A Film Premiere on Citizen Diplomacy, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Homerule Now Stickers, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Parliamentary Procedure Lessons, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Paul Robeson Friendship Society of Washington DC, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Paul Robeson Friendship Society of Correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Grenada: A Preliminary Report, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Index of Documents for Public Release - II, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Central Committee Correspondence/Minutes/Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - US Grenada Friendship Society Sponsorship Reciept, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Journey to Mount Robeson in the Soviet Union Brochure, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - The Greatest All American Day Info, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Grenada Revolution Commeration Invitation, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - American Friends Service Committee Correspondence, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Boston Grenada Solidarity Committee Press Release, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Comrade Tony Boatain Bullet Point, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Guilty by Association Tony and Susan Alamo Brochure, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Reception Programs, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Address and Phone Number Lists, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Newspapers on Grenada, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Unitarian Universalist Papers, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Philippines- American Relations, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - American Lung Association Bulletin: The Spitting Image of Smoking, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Freedom for Ziad Stickers, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Chairs Present List, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Notebook of Possible Commanders of Grenada's Military Region, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ministry of Defence - USSR Certificate, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Minutes of Organising Committee - 18-4-83, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Political/Economic Bureau, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cadet Correspondence, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Extraordinary Meeting of the Central Committee NJM, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Work flaw Guidelines for the Party's Propaganda Department, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Political Education in Armed Forces Paper, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Material Means Received from Foreign Countries, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Embajada De Grenada en Cuba, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Ian Jacobs Paper, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Minutes of Meeting of Committee of Economic Ministers, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Bulletin from the Main Political Department, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Report on Meeting of PB and CC, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Sixth Sitting of Central Committee Plenary, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Central Committee Meeting Notes 8/24/1983 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - USSR and Grenada Agreement, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - USSR, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Republic of Cuba and Revolutionary Government of Grenada Protocol, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - People's Revolutionary Government of Grenada and Government of Democratic People's Republic of Korea Agreement, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - List of Individual Documents Released November 4 1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Index of Captured Documents from Grenada, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - CDE Strachan Papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Partido Comunista de Cuba/ Comite Central, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - On the Possible Establishment of a State Trading Corporation for Effecting Grenada's Trade with Socialist Countries, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Meeting Notes: Chiefs of Staff SSR and Grenada, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Construction Plans, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Schedule for the Minster of Defense of Grenada, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - GM of CM Mon. Sept. 26th, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - On Cuba's Response to the Issue Paper, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Headquarters Notes on Members, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 1977 Inaugural Guide to Washington (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - State Legislative Statistics, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - The Congressional Black Caucus Tenth Annual Legislative Weekend Salute to the Black Family, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Democrats have to take a Stand Article, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - A Decade of Home Rule: Anniversary Celebration of Home Rule, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Report on the General Congress of the World Center for the Resistance of Imperialism, Zionism, Racism, and Reaction, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Report on Socialist International Bureau Meeting, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Order of Ambajada de Granada 5 Avenida, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Report on Peace Meetings in Lisbon, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Grenada Site Analysis, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Act of Delivery and Reception City of St. George's, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - In Cooperation Between the New Jewel Movement of Grenada and the Communist Party in the Soviet Union, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Grenada Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Meeting Notes: CDE Hudson and CDE Lepito, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Abstract: Grenada's Trends Preceding Maurice Bishop's Murder, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Hilda Mason, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Letter from Tom Richards, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Programs, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Achievements of the People's Revolutionary Government of Grenada, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Ward One Task Force Correspondence, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Salt of the Earth Inc. By Laws, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Adams Morgan Advisory Board Neighborhood Commission 1-C, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - National Coordinating Council Meeting Minutes - U.S Grenada, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - United States and Grenada Relations, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - From the Tourist Desk Reprint from Black Enterprise 9/81, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - James E. Drew Accounting and Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Caribbean Seminar Letter and Response Form, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Camp Artek Program, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - L Zapata Correspondence, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Grenada: Press Releases - Statements and New Releases, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Declaration of the Jamaica Peace Committee, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Everybody's Magazine, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Caribbean Perspective: A Magazine of World Affairs, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Caribbean Conference of Churches: Jamaica Peace Committee, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Coalition to Stop US Intervention in Grenada Roster Outreach Committee, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Grenada News: Prime Minister's Message to Grenadians in North America, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Photos: Bright New Dawn Free Grenada, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Destination Mt. Paul Robeson, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Rules for Black Unity, Survival and Progress and Operation Instructions, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Beat Back Destabilizers, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Congressional Record Articles, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Decolonization Committee Takes up Questions of Puerto Rico, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Chapter Member Letters, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - The Churchman: A Humanistic Approach to Religion, Ethics and Education, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Meeting of Integrationist Workers Statement, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Military in the Caribbean Articles, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Statement by H.E Mr. Maurice Bishop Prime Minster and Minister of Foreign Affairs of Grenada at the 34th Session of the United Nations Grenada Assembly, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - CIA Too Hot for Grenada to Handle, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Proposal for Two Day Conference "In Solidarity with Grenada", 1981 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - An Agreement: US Grenada Society for Friendship and Cultural Relations, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - D.C Coalition to Stop the US Invasion of Grenada, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Third World Women: Our Continuing Struggle, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Guyana Information Bulletin, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - PPP Statement, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Statehood Papers - Correspondence and Articles, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Constitution of the State of New Columbia, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Vote on Proposed Constitution Newspaper, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - District of Columbia Statehood Constitutional Convention Drafting Session, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - American Psychological Association, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Statehood House Bills, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Statehood Newspaper Articles, 1982-1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Islamic/Christian Dialogue, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Halloween Party Invitations, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Statehood Correspondence Papers and Memos, 1980-1984 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Windfall Tax and Land Tax Articles and Papers, 1967-1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Goals and Policies for DC - First District Element of Comprehensive Plan, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Articles on Congress, 1980-1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Caribbean Articles, 1976-1984 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - US Grenada Newspaper Articles, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Basis Point Publication, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Territories and Insular Possessions, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - July 11th the Liberty Bell Train to Philadelphia, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hearing Board Report II, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - John F. Graham V. Ruth Clusen Transcript, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - DC Voting and Election Newspaper Articles, 1977-1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - A Conference on Alternative Public Policy for Northeastern Cities, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Julius Hobson, 1968-1983 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Julia Hobson Articles, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Washington Star, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Grassroots: National Publication of the People's Party, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Full Employment, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Export/Import, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - NYC Urban Coalition Housing Rehabilitation Task Force, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Economic Principles of the Torah and Messages from Chief Seattle, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Comprehensive Plan, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Civic Center: An Economic Development Project, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Office and Professional Employees International Union, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - DC Tuberculosis and Respiratory Disease Association, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Airforce Magazine, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Letters and Cards, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Surveillance Legislation Outline, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Daily Rag, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - 1985 A Look Ahead: Population Forecasts (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Local Black Press Contact Sheet, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - PHUB Meeting/Minutes/Agendas/Papers/Ads (1 of 4), 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - PHUB Meeting/Minutes/Agendas/Papers/Ads (2 of 4), 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - PHUB Meeting/Minutes/Agendas/Papers/Ads (3 of 4), 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - PHUB Meeting/Minutes/Agendas/Papers/Ads (4 of 4), 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Federation of Citizens Associations Correspondence, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Press Book: The New, 1967-1969 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - D.C. Statehood Initiative, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - D.C. Statehood and Politics, 1975-1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Dupont Plaza Hotel Receipts, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Foster Grandparents Program, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - D.C Statehood Commission, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Government of the District of Columbia Board of Elections and Ethics Voter Registration, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Operation Instructions Booklet, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Walter E. Fauntroy and Congress, 1981-1985 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - 12th World Festival of Youth and Students, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Itinerary Draft, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - 1982 Tax Tips for the Union Members (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Hiroshima Japan, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Black British Standing Conference Against Aparthied, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Paul Robeson Friendship Society of Washington D.C. Correspondence and Ads, 1978-1991 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Union Friendship Pamphlets, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Briefing Book for H.R. 51 the D.C. Statehood Bill, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Statehood Compact Commission, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1992 Five Hundred Years After Columbus: A Work of Historical Reference (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Friendship, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - American Declaration of the Rights and Duties of Man, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - United Way/ United Labor Agency, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Freedom of Assembly, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Coalition to Stop U.S. Internvention in Grenada Roster, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship Inc. (1 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship Inc. (2 of 2), 1984 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Friendship Society 1979 (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Friendship Society 1979 (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Friendship Society 1980 (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Friendship Society 1980 (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Friendship Society, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Friendship Society 1983 (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Friendship Society 1983 (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Friendship Society, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Union, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Democratic Slate - 1968, 1965-1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Adams Morgan, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Historic Washington, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Health (2 of 2), 1973-1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Health (1 of 2), 1976-1983 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - National Children's Island, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Internation Affairs, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Article from "The Nation", 1981 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - International Conference for Peace, Security and Cooperation In the Mediterranean, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - World Conference for the Eradication of Racism and Racial Discrimination, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The AD Hoc Committee to Memorialize Paul Robeson, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Friendship Society, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - DC Committee for a Dialogue on Disarmament and Dtente, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Speakers - Acceptances, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Preamble, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - For Jo Butler, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Speakers List, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Expenditures/World Peace Conference, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Master Copies, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Receipts, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Bills, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Soviet Union, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Julius W. Hobson Middle School, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous and Folder with Notes, 1979-1982 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - D.C. Statehood Correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Voter Registration Reform, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - International Affairs, 1974-1981 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - District of Columbia Tax Issues, 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Comparative Data on DC Statehood, 1977-1984 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Josephine Butler DC City Council, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (1 of 2), 1978 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - National Council of American -Soviet Friendship (2 of 2), 1978 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Paul Robeson News Articles, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - The Washington Afro Americn Article, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - City Council, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - USSR News Article, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Paul Robeson Articles and Friendship Society Papers, 1976-1989 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - New World Review, 1977-1984 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Intervention in Afganistan, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Guide to NIH (National Institutes of Health), undated (Box 19, Folder 4)